## Catherine Hellsten

cyh3131@rit.edu 210.852.9882

Cover Letter & Professional Resume

03/28/13

Search Committee Center For Residence Life 113 Riverknoll Rochester, NY 14623

Dear Search Committee,

I am writing this letter to express my interest in the Center for Residence Life's open position for the Community Advocate Assistantship. As a graduate student of Rochester Institute of Technology's Master of Fine Arts in Imaging Arts program, I am involved in many areas centered around group activities and participate both as a leader and as an individual. In particular, I am currently a photography instructor for non-major undergraduate students. This position allows me to be a leader of a diverse set of individuals working towards a common goal. Guiding these students to foster independence in my field, while constantly focusing my attention on the group as a whole has challenged my awareness as an instructor. I look forward to the possibility of continuing to develop professional leadership and support skills in a larger community in our university.

Having spent nine years between my undergraduate and graduate years studying and working abroad in South Korea and Japan, I feel that I can bring an open mindedness and understanding towards diverse perspectives to the Center for Residence Life. Being in an environment that was culturally and socially different from my own, I was inspired to redefine my definition of community and my place in it. I did this by learning the languages, participating in local cultural classes, and volunteering in the community. Upon return to the US and at the start of my graduate studies I have eagerly transmitted this enthusiasm for the skills and perspective I learned abroad to my personal studies as well as to the community within the university. I am now an active participant of several university organizations through the roles of both member and leader. I feel very fortunate to be a student at RIT, which offers me so many opportunities to give and receive support tailored towards my skill set and individuality. My independent studies and my involvement within the university constantly push me to grow as an individual and as a member and leader of a larger team.

With my experience and belief behind empowering the individuals within a community, I feel I could genuinely support the mission of the Center for Campus Life. In turn, I am excited about the possibility of growing as both an individual and as a professional with the guidance of an organization with a mindset similar to my own. Thank you very much for your time and consideration and please do not hesitate to contact me with any questions.

Sincerely, Catherine Hellsten

Professional Resume

#### **Education**

Master of Fine Arts (Candidate), Imaging Arts, Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, New York, 2014

Bachelor of Arts, Studio Art, University of Texas, Austin, Texas, 2002 Bachelor of Fine Arts with Honors, Art History, University of Texas, Austin, Texas, 2002

### **Professional Experience**

2012-13	Photography Instructor (Introduction to Photography for Non-Majors),
	College of Imaging Arts, Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, New
	York

Instruct non-major students on the basics of digital camera functions, printing guidelines, photographic concepts, Photoshop, and Lightroom.

2012 Graduate Teaching Assistant for Greg Halpern (Photo Arts 1),
College of Imaging Arts, Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, New
York

Assist instructor with critiques, digital camera functions, basic photography concepts, Photoshop, and Lightroom.

- 2012 *Portrait Photographer*, Our 365 Portraits, San Antonio, Texas Create traditional portraits of families and individuals in a portable studio setting. Sales and friendly service.
- 2011-12 English Instructor, Goduk Elementary School, Seoul, South Korea
  Head English teacher to elementary students instructing the basics
  of English grammar, reading, writing and conversation.
- 2010-11 English Instructor, Jindai Junior High School, Tokyo, Japan
  Instruct elementary students in the basics of English grammar and conversation.
- 2008-10 English Instructor, Jamsin Elementary School, Seoul, South Korea
  Head English teacher to elementary students instructing the basics
  of English grammar, reading, writing and conversation.
- 2007 *Manager, Portrait Photographer,* Olan Mills, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania Create traditional portraits of families and individuals in a studio setting. Editing images, sales, friendly service, and administrative responsibilities.

# Awards / Grants

2012	Rochester Institute of Technology Merit Scholarship
2011	Seoul Photography Club Challenge
2000-01	General Fee Grant, College of Fine Art, University of Texas
1999-02	University of Texas University Honors
1999-02	University of Texas College Scholar for the College of Fine Art
1998-02	Texas Public Education Grant, University of Texas
1997-98	Tuition Scholarship for Resident Students, University of Texas

# **Memberships**

Rochester Institute of Technology Graduate Photography Association, Member since 2012 Rochester Institute of Technology College of Imaging Arts Graduate Executive Board, Representative since 2012

Scottsville Veterinary Adoptions, Volunteer Photographer since 2012 Society for Photographic Education, Member since 2012 American Photographic Artists, Member since 2012 Mannam International Volunteer Organization, Member since 2011 Mannam Photography Group, Member since 2011